<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Integration | Build and Release]]></title>
  <link href="http://lifuzu.com/blog/categories/integration/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://lifuzu.com/"/>
  <updated>2016-05-01T22:35:50-07:00</updated>
  <id>http://lifuzu.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Richard Li]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Continuous Integration/Delivery Pipeline]]></title>
    <link href="http://lifuzu.com/blog/2016/04/13/continuous-integration-slash-delivery-pipeline/"/>
    <updated>2016-04-13T09:42:18-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://lifuzu.com/blog/2016/04/13/continuous-integration-slash-delivery-pipeline</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-vYfGCI7QdNQ/Vw52k6Q4XdI/AAAAAAAAEHg/FrNo5qzDlYY8QcdY0bzU4FOf6EuTUs-XgCLcB/s600/Gas-Pipelines-in-Columbia.jpg" title="Gas-Pipelines-in-Columbia.jpg" alt="enter image description here" /></p>

<p>Based on several software release engineering system, such as: Jenkins (include a bunch of Plugins), Gerrit, Git, Mocha, Nodejs and etc, we create a continuous integration pipeline to control source code, validation change(s), build artifact, report test results and deploy the artifacts to various deployment servers, just as: dev, staging, production (all groups). Here is a draft diagram we are trying to implement for Content Stream Application Service:</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><img src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-H3FwqFg7z38/Vw50_hFK4tI/AAAAAAAAEHU/1lUUkyBENdUb64L1LA640DUUNewtn03dwCLcB/s1000/Continuous+Integration+Pipeline.png" title="Continuous Integration Pipeline.png" alt="Continuous Integration Pipeline" /></p>

<p>Here are some explanations for a specific job of content stream, for example:</p>

<ul>
<li>The job contentstream-<strong>patchset</strong> will be triggered automatically when
one change is being pushed to Gerrit for review, it will set verify
bit ‘+1’ for the review if the build successfully; or warn the
submitter of the change if the build fail;</li>
<li>When any change is merged to the branch, for example, ‘master’, the
job contentstream-<strong>master</strong> will be triggered automatically to verify
the change if it affects the branch;</li>
<li>The job contentstream-master-<strong>release</strong> is to make tag, push the tag to server
to label a version of source code, which should be deployed to
deployment servers some time later;</li>
<li>The deployment jobs, like contentstream-master-<strong>deploy</strong>-to-* will deploy the source code to the dev|stag|prod (group1, group2, &hellip;) servers according to the version which labeled on the release job as above;</li>
</ul>


<blockquote><p>Written with <a href="https://stackedit.io/">StackEdit</a>.</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
